<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Network Forensics :: Tag :: SBK Hugo Site</title><link>https://bernie6401.github.io/tags/network-forensics/index.html</link><description/><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bernie6401.github.io/tags/network-forensics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CyberDefender - PoisonedCredentials</title><link>https://bernie6401.github.io/security/practice/cyberdefender/network-forensic/cyberdefender---poisonedcredentials/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bernie6401.github.io/security/practice/cyberdefender/network-forensic/cyberdefender---poisonedcredentials/index.html</guid><description>CyberDefender - PoisonedCredentials Challenge: https://cyberdefenders.org/blueteam-ctf-challenges/146#nav-questions
:::spoiler TOC [TOC] :::
Scenario Your organization’s security team has detected a surge in suspicious network activity. There are concerns that LLMNR (Link-Local Multicast Name Resolution) and NBT-NS (NetBIOS Name Service) poisoning attacks may be occurring within your network. These attacks are known for exploiting these protocols to intercept network traffic and potentially compromise user credentials. Your task is to investigate the network logs and examine captured network traffic.</description></item><item><title>CyberDefender - PsExec Hunt</title><link>https://bernie6401.github.io/security/practice/cyberdefender/network-forensic/cyberdefender---psexec-hunt/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bernie6401.github.io/security/practice/cyberdefender/network-forensic/cyberdefender---psexec-hunt/index.html</guid><description>CyberDefender - PsExec Hunt :::spoiler [TOC] :::
Scenario Our Intrusion Detection System (IDS) has raised an alert, indicating suspicious lateral movement activity involving the use of PsExec. To effectively respond to this incident, your role as a SOC Analyst is to analyze the captured network traffic stored in a PCAP file.
==Q1== In order to effectively trace the attacker’s activities within our network, can you determine the IP address of the machine where the attacker initially gained access?</description></item><item><title>CyberDefender - Tomcat Takeover</title><link>https://bernie6401.github.io/security/practice/cyberdefender/network-forensic/cyberdefender---tomcat-takeover/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bernie6401.github.io/security/practice/cyberdefender/network-forensic/cyberdefender---tomcat-takeover/index.html</guid><description>CyberDefender - Tomcat Takeover Challenge: https://cyberdefenders.org/blueteam-ctf-challenges/135#nav-questions
:::spoiler TOC [TOC] :::
Scenario Our SOC team has detected suspicious activity on one of the web servers within the company’s intranet. In order to gain a deeper understanding of the situation, the team has captured network traffic for analysis. This pcap file potentially contains a series of malicious activities that have resulted in the compromise of the Apache Tomcat web server. We need to investigate this incident further.</description></item><item><title>CyberDefender - WebStrike</title><link>https://bernie6401.github.io/security/practice/cyberdefender/network-forensic/cyberdefender---webstrike/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bernie6401.github.io/security/practice/cyberdefender/network-forensic/cyberdefender---webstrike/index.html</guid><description>CyberDefender - WebStrike Challenge: https://cyberdefenders.org/blueteam-ctf-challenges/149
:::spoiler TOC [TOC] :::
Scenario An anomaly was discovered within our company’s intranet as our Development team found an unusual file on one of our web servers. Suspecting potential malicious activity, the network team has prepared a pcap file with critical network traffic for analysis for the security team, and you have been tasked with analyzing the pcap.
==Q1== Understanding the geographical origin of the attack aids in geo-blocking measures and threat intelligence analysis. What city did the attack originate from?</description></item></channel></rss>